Inventory of the Ivan Alekseevich Vladimirov paintings
Hoover Institution Archives
Ivan Alekseevich Vladimirov paintings
1918-1923
24001
Hoover Institution Archives
4 oversize boxes (4.7 linear feet)
Depicts scenes of daily life during the Russian Revolution. Digital copies available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org
Vladimirov, I. A. (Ivan Alekseevich), 1869-1947.
Access
Originals may not be used without permission of the Archivist. Digital copies available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1924.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org
Scope and Content note
Depicts scenes of daily life during the Russian Revolution. All works are watercolors except where otherwise indicated.
Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921--Pictorial works.; Painting.
- 1. Hungry ones in Petrograd dividing a dead horse in the street, 1919 (Box 1)
- 2. Rich merchants and Russian noblemen set to pulling out rubbish from yards, 1920
- 3. Waiting to receive an eighth of a pound of bread, 1919
- 4. Requisition of banknotes, obligations, etc., from the treasury of Vavelberg Bank in Petrograd, 1919
- 5. A lesson on communism for the Russian peasants, 1922
- 6. Russian priests conveyed to judgment (a scene on the Nevsky Prospect), 1922
- 7. Hungry workmen in Petrograd robbing a military lorry of bread, 1920
- 8. Russian peasants returning home after pillaging a country house of a rich landlord (near Pskoff), 1919
- 9. Russian clergymen hiding church treasures in a new grave in a cemetery (near Luga), 1922
- 10. A landlord and a Russian Pope condemned to death by a revolutionary tribunal (at Valdai), 1919
- 11. Workmen breaking down wooden houses for fuel (Petrograd), 1920
- 12-14. [Not held at Hoover Institution Archives]
- 15. Revolutionary workmen and soldiers robbing a wine-shop (Petrograd), 1919 January
- 16. Hard labor for rich merchants, nobles and criminals during the years of revolution (1919-1922) (Box 2)
- 17. Vandalism of the revolutionaries, a scene in one of the rooms of the Winter Place, 1918 December
- 18. Requisition of flour from rich peasants in a village (a scene near Pskoff), 1922
- 19. Hungry days in Petrograd - hungry people of all classes eating their portions at the doors of a "Communal dining room,", 1919
- 20. Miserable life of Russian nobles and persons of high rank during the revolution (drawn from nature in the home of General Buturline), 1919
- 21. Requisition of cattle for the Red Army in a village near Luga, 1920 June
- 22. Hard labor for Russian clergymen. A group of Russian priests forced to clear the barrack stables, 1918 December 22
- 23. Burial of a workman who was not a communist. Communists are always buried magnificently, 1920 January
- 24. Hungry days in Petrograd. A lady and her daughter searching for potato peelings and herring-heads to eat. Drawn from nature, 1919 January
- 25. A man dead of hunger--a prey for hungry dogs. Drawn from nature (Petrograd), 1919 January
- 26. Miserable life of intelligent and noble Russian families in Petrograd during the revolution. A family of an engineer dragging home some fuel, 1919 January
- 27. Petrograd without water. Frequently the water supply was stopped and the inhabitants were obliged to carry water from the Neva, 1919 October
- 28. Free trade in Petrograd. Military helping themselves in a market place, 1922 December (Box 3)
- 29. Hungry years in Petrograd. Inhabitants returning home with their dinners from a communal soup kitchen, 1919 November
- 30. Hungry years in Petrograd. Changing merchandise for provisions in a village near a railway station, 1919 June
- 31. A foreigner attacked by cigarette sellers in Petrograd, 1923
- 32. A distinguished general (Prince Vasiltchikoff) in his present position. Sic Transit Gloria Mundi (Petrograd), 1922 June
- 33. Group of Bolsheviks - man and two girls in a field. Oil on panel
- 34. Group of Bolsheviks on a train. Oil on panel
- 35. Russian family, 1923
- 36. The father's funeral
- 37. Remains of a wealthy house
- 38. Hungry times in Petrograd, 1919
- 39. Requisition of firewood
- 40. Group of Russian sailors playing cards amidst ruined buildings. Oil on panel (Box 4)
- 41. Two boys arrested for stealing. Photographic reproduction